MARIA MCGLADE SEGOVIA

MARKETING MANAGER

+34 618 821 295 | mariamcglade@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/maria-mcglade

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Data-savvy marketing professional with a proven track record in product launches and data analysis. Fluent in four languages, combines data analytics, UX insights and go-to-market expertise. Turning ideas into campaigns that engage, inspire, and deliver results.

KEY SKILLS

- · Campaign management
- Data analysis and reporting
- Marketing automation

- · Project management
- Content marketing and SEO
- UX and customer research

EXPERIENCE

Product Marketing Communications Specialist

Elekta (Healthtech)

Nov 2023 - Present

London, UK

- Led the global launch of new software campaigns, increasing qualified leads by 30%
- Monitored competitor and market activity and refined messaging accordingly, leading to a 15% uplift in campaign engagement
- Developed targeted content and materials that boosted customer engagement metrics by 20%

Marketing Database & Reporting Intern

Elekta (Healthtech)

May 2023 - Nov 2023

London, UK

- Built dashboards in Salesforce and QlikSense to monitor campaign metrics, enabling teams to make datadriven decisions and cutting reporting time by 30%
- Cleaned and updated Salesforce data, improving targeting accuracy and reducing duplicate records by 25%
- Built automated email campaigns in Salesforce that increased open rates by 10% for target audiences

Librarian While studying H-FARM (Education)

Sep 2022 - May 2023

Venice, Italy

Bartender & Social Media Manager | While studying

Montpeliers Ltd (Hospitality) Edinburgh, UK

Jun 2019 - Dec 2020 Edinburgh, UK

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Digital Marketing & Data Analytics

H-FARM College (University of Chichester)

Sep 2022 - Nov 2023

Venice, Italy

- Participated in challenges and hackathons with De'Longhi & Juventus
- Nurtured curiosity for UX & data

Bachelor of Arts, Business Administration with Marketing

Edinburgh Napier University

Sep 2017 - Oct 2022 Edinburgh, UK

ADDITIONAL SKILLS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Languages: English (native), Spanish (native), Italian (C2) and French (B2)

Certifications: Analyse Data with Python, CAD and Digital Manufacturing, Start Up Lab, Project Management

for Innovation, Economics of Blockchain